# Adrián Moreno Peña Engineering Leader

# Hello, nice to meet you!

I am **Adrián**. I am Spanish, live for 4 years in Copenhagen (Valby) with my wife and son. I have a **broad experience working among different cultures**, having lived before for 6 years in Amsterdam, and started my career in Spain. I thrive on diverse, multi-cultural environments and are able to navigate cultural differences with positivity.

By formation I am a **computer engineer with a Master's Degree in Project Management**. But that has not defined my professional career as much as my passion for making teams understand each other, building empathy across functions and aligning incentives and objectives in the organizations I've been part of.

My career expands over 17 years, including over a decade of hands-on software development on high scalability and availability systems for web and mobile applications.

Technical systems are nothing without a **sustainable business model** behind them, and I have hands-on experience in multiple industries, such as SaaS in Fintech, *direct to consumer* e-commerce, cross-country omnichannel e-commerce, or referral marketing networks.

On the way of working, I am a firm believer in **multi disciplinary teams and breaking silos**. I have implemented DevOps practices (monitoring, alerting and observability, incident response, "everything as code", ...) in teams I have been part of, as well as applied agile concepts (escaping from "agile the right way", favoring the right agile for the team).

To me, leading is doing what *has to be done*, and acting in a way that creates trust, empowers people to "dare to try", and fosters a healthy curiosity to always aim to improve.

I have had my own company myself, and having been part of scale-ups and start-ups, am in my comfort zone balancing speed with cost-control, paying technical debt while innovating on customer-facing value.

If you ask my peers, they'll highlight my high energy with can-do mindset, self-driven nature while keeping a strong team spirit (yes, I know it sounds like a contraction, but we agree I do act in such way:-), and a genuine interest on making others better. In comparison with engineering peers, I get as a highlight my strong business sense, with focus on developing sustainable product strategies (including economical aspects as well as architectural, organizational design, etc).

Hoping to talk to you soon,

Adrián Moreno Peña

# Key highlights

Energetic, with high drive and strong team player.

Software Engineer with strong business acumen.

Adaptable leader with a focus on evolutionary change and culture shift.

Experience and comfortable as

- Individual contributor.
- Team manager.
- Manager of managers.

Experience in multiple sectors:

- Omnichannel E-commerce
- In-house, agency and consulting.
- Subscription-based SaaS.
- Digital-native app development.

Experience as general manager and board member.

Worked across cultures in international environments, based in 3 different countries.

Multi-disciplinary technologist:

- Mobile and web apps.
- System integrations.
- Platform and API development.

# Adrián Moreno Peña ngineering Leader

# Work experience

Engineering Manager -- Director of Engineering -- VP of Engineering, Tribe Lead SumUp. Copenhagen (Denmark)

Guided a cross-functional team of 30 members across 4 teams to evolve a SaaS platform by driving alignment on the technical roadmap and ensuring clear stakeholder management.

Managed the P&L for the business unit, overseeing the strategy, product and technical roadmap and execution, including Go-To-Market efforts.

As VP of Engineering, established the global Incident Response process, connecting with Engineering, Governance, Risk and Compliance and Operation teams (~900 FTEs). Revamped the global status page architecture and

- Maintained yearly recurring SaaS revenue through a brand and platform migration, and introducing a new subscription plan.
- Increased >20% MAU by introducing a new product line.
- Reduced time required to coordinate incidents by >60%.
- Mitigated regulatory risks and improved collaboration across functional areas around business-critical services.

2019-21

Technical Lead → Engineering Manager VanMoof. Amsterdam (Netherlands)

Solidified the technology infrastructure for a Direct-To-Consumer brand by insourcing the e-commerce and subscription platform, including integration with ERP and CRM, and other customer facing and internal portals using in the vertically integrated brand experience. Led external and internal teams, managing and coaching employees and and structuring the team during hyper-growth phase.

- Improved CI/CD times for e-commerce by >50%, reducing downtime by >70%.
- Led automated QA and code standardization efforts, lowering production defects by 30%.

2017-19

Technical Lead Emakina.NL. Amsterdam (Netherlands)

Technical Lead for the largest contract the agency had got, an international e-commerce, CRM, integration and service platform in the Salesforce ecosystem (SFCC, Service Cloud, Mulesoft). Guiding on best practices, overseeing the technical execution and scoping of projects and integration of deliverables, including enterprise architecture and accessibility requirements. Collaborating with the Marketing team on improving the ecommerce KPIs and ad spending.

- Championed accessibility improvements, achieving WCAG 2.1 level AA compliance.
- Integrated with PIM and DAM systems, lowering time to market new campaigns.

2015-17

CTO Pocket Media. Amsterdam (Netherlands)

Led the technology team (15 FTE) in developing a new SaaS platform for native advertising across Android, iOS, web, and Unity. Defined product roadmaps, milestones, and talent acquisition plans, aligning with company strategy and vision as part of the management

- Development of a new SaaS platform for Native advertisement (Android, iOS, web, Unity).
- Operated in-house applications and games with thousands of DAU.
- Performance improvement of +1000% (by re-platforming PHP → Golang).

2015

**Senior Mobile Applications Developer** 

The Mobile Company. Amsterdam (Netherlands)

Developed innovative new apps for iOS and Android (Bluetooth BLE beacons technology), and maintained apps (including top Dutch apps).

• Drove adoption of Agile principles within customer interactions, resulting in a 30% improvement in deliverable velocity and enhanced alignment between deliverables and client

2011-15

Co-Founder, Technical Lead Zadia Software. Santiago (Spain)

Co-Founded a bootstrapped development studio, leading and coordinating a team of up to 5 engineers, while doubling the revenue every year. Providing IT and consulting services focused on web and mobile development.

- Spearheaded the entire sales process from initial client contact to project proposal delivery, resulting in a 100% YoY revenue growth.
- Drove technical execution of web and mobile applications development by coordinating a team of 5 engineers.

2007-11

Analyst Programmer Bahía Software, Coremain. Santiago (Spain)

Navigated complex regulatory landscapes across healthcare, banking and the projects for the public sector, with full compliance while introducing modern development practices and

• Introduced new technologies (jQuery, Drupal), enhancing developer productivity and enabling new business opportunities (leading to new public contracts).

### Information

Name Adrián Moreno Peña

June 4th, 1986 **Birth** 

**Nationality** Spanish

Spanish, Galician (native); Languages

English (full proficiency); Danish, Dutch, French, Portuguese (basic)

**Phone** +4531579827

info@adrianmoreno.info **Email** 

**Online** 





### Skills

#### Hard skills (>10years)

- Programming technologies: native mobile iOS & Android, responsible web, Javascript/ Typescript, PHP, Java...
- DevOps/SysAdmin: Infrastructure as Code (ie: Terraform, CDK), observability (logs, metrics, traces), cloud and on-premises computing
- UX and accessibility (including compliance)
- E-commerce, Content Management Systems and CRM: Salesforce, Wordpress, Drupal, Magento, ...

#### Management (>10 years)

- Coaching and personal development
- Career framework design
- Manager of teams; manager of managers.

#### Techniques (>10 years)

- Agile methodologies (Scrum, Kanban, etc)
- Continuous Integration & Delivery (CI/CD)
- Vendor selection and contract negotiation
- Product management
- Roadmap alignment

## Education

Master in Projects Management University of Santiago de Compostela.

#### **Technical Engineering in Computer** Systems

University of Santiago de Compostela.

Specializations: Internet and Networking.

## Courses & other

Team Leadership Program for Directors The Performance Coach, 2016

Experience in public speaking: Podcast guest, Toastmasters, Meetup/ conference speaker

#### Teaching experience

Management board member of sport clubs: Campo da Angustia football club, Amsterdam Triathlon and Cycling Club, /tri club denmark triathlon club).